Inventory of the Colby E. "Babe" Slater Collection D-394
University of California, Davis General Library, Dept. of Special Collections
- Scrapbook, 1924; Series 6; 46 folders.
  - Newspaper clippings, 1924; D394.6.2; 12 folders (Box 4, Folder 5-15)
    - Clipping, Le tournoi olympique: le match États-Unis-France, [1924]; D394.6.2.59 (Box 4, Folder 11.11)
      Photograph. Caption: "L'Américain Rogers (13), qui vient d'exécuter du saut d'obstacle par-dessus Dupont, lance la balle à un de ses partenaires. Lasserre et Etchberry à gauche se portent en défense. A droite on aperçoit couché à terre Jaurréguy, qui vient d'être victime de la collision violente qui l'obligea à quitter le terrain."
    - Clipping, Le tournoi olympique: le match États-Unis-France, [1924]; D394.6.2.60 (Box 4, Folder 11.12)
      Commentary on match accompanied by photograph. Caption: "Une touche. Malgré les efforts de Cassayet et de Piquiral, Valentino s'empare de la balle. Derrière eux Farrish et Bioussa."
    - Clipping, Le tournoi olympique: le match États-Unis-France, [1924]; D394.6.2.61 (Box 4, Folder 11.13)
      Photograph. Caption: "Une superbe démonstration de l'efficacité du plaquage américain dont Béhotéguy et Jauréguy font les frais."
    - Clipping, La victoire olympique des États-Unis sur la France, [1924]; D394.6.2.62 (Box 4, Folder 11.14)
    - Clipping, Le tournoi olympique: le match États-Unis-France, [1924]; D394.6.2.63 (Box 4, Folder 11.15)
      Photograph. Caption is missing.
    - Clipping, Demain, à 16 heures, au Stade de Colombes: France-États-Unis?, [1924]; D394.6.2.64 (Box 4, Folder 11.16)
    - Clipping, L'Amérique gagne le Tournoi Olympique contre la France, [1924]; D394.6.2.65 (Box 4, Folder 11.17)
    - Clipping, Demain la France se heurtera à l'Amérique: Le Coq vaincra-t-il la bannière étoilée?, [1924]; D394.6.2.66 (Box 4, Folder 11.18)
    - Clipping, American Olympic rugby players win first match abroad, [1924]; D394.6.2.67 (Box 4, Folder 12.1)
      Photograph of players on field. Caption: "This interesting photo shows Uncle Sam's boys being cheered by the Devonport Services at Plymouth, Eng., after the English team had been defeated by a score of 25 to 3. The British good sportsmanship is unfailing."
      Rugby football teams -- United States; Rugby football; Slater, Colby E.; Olympic Games (8th: 1924: Paris, France)
    - Clipping, Battle starts in stands as players score, [1924]; D394.6.2.68; 3 clippings (Box 4, Folder 12.2)
    - Clipping, London Times. Rugby football: Americans' victory at Olympic Games, May 19, 1924; D394.6.2.69 (Box 4, Folder 12.3)
    - Clipping, [New York Herald]. Rugby game reflections, [1924]; D394.6.2.70; 2 clippings (Box 4, Folder 12.4)
      Letter to the editor.
    - Clipping, Crowd unfair at clean game, say officials, [1924]; D394.6.2.71 (Box 4, Folder 12.5)
    - Clipping, Boos rain on Americans in spite of clean game, [1924]; D394.6.2.72 (Box 4, Folder 12.6)
    - Clipping, [Team photograph], [1924]; D394.6.2.73 (Box 4, Folder 12.7)
      Caption: "American Rugby Team -- Another example of our athletic supremacy."
      Rugby football teams -- United States; Olympic Games (8th: 1924: Paris, France); Slater, Colby E.; Slater, Norman B. (Norman Bernard), 1894-1979
    - Clipping, Chicago Tribune. Beats American at rugby game, May 19, 1924; D394.6.2.74 (Box 4, Folder 12.8)
    - Clipping, American Olympic rugby team wins brilliant victory in Paris, [1924]; D394.6.2.75 (Box 4, Folder 12.9)
      Photograph. Caption: "Action snapshots taken during contest in Colombes Stadium, in which our players conquered the French by a score of 17-3; some of the spectators became excited, hissed the Americans and started a small-sized riot in the stands."
    - Clipping, Getting into shape for victory, [1924]; D394.6.2.76 (Box 4, Folder 12.10)
      Photograph. Clipping: "Members of the American rugby team practising before game in which they defeated the French for the Olympic championship recently."
    - Clipping, U.S. defeats rugby team to 17 to 3: Brilliant attack wins decisive victory for Americans, by Leo Brady, [1924]; D394.6.2.77; Clipping is torn at the bottom. (Box 4, Folder 13.1)
    - Clipping, French, beaten at Rugby, beat up Americans: Players deplore acts of their own fans, [1924]; D394.6.2.78; 2 clippings (Box 4, Folder 13.2)
    - Clipping, New Tork Times. U.S. Team is hissed by French when it wins Olympic title, 1924; D394.6.2.79; 4 clippings (Box 4, Folder 13.3)
    - Clipping, French praise U.S. rugby team, [1924]; D394.6.2.80; 2 clippings (Box 4, Folder 13.4)
    - Clipping, American rugby players and flag hissed by Paris, [1924]; D394.6.2.81; 3 clippings (Box 4, Folder 13.5)
      Rugby football; Rugby football teams -- United States; Olympic Games (8th: 1924: Paris, France); Slater, Colby E.
    - Clipping, Herald Tribune. U.S. aroused by incident at Colombes, May 20, 1924; D394.6.2.82; 5 clippings (Box 4, Folder 13.6)
    - Clipping, American rugby players are robbed; Paris paper criticizes their methods, [1924]; D394.6.2.83 (Box 4, Folder 13.7)
    - Clipping, American Olympic victors hissed by French, [1924]; D394.6.2.84 (Box 4, Folder 13.8)
      Photograph of players in scrum. Caption: "The picture shows the team that defeated France 17 to 3 in final contest in Colombes stadium."
    - Clipping, [Woodland Daily Democrat]. Slater bringing home gold victory statue. Writes his own version of American history, May 22, 1924; D394.6.2.85; 2 clippings (Box 4, Folder 14.1)
    - Clipping, [Woodland Daily Democrat]. "Babe" Slater returns to Woodland; is greeted by old football mates, [1924]; D394.6.2.86; 2 clippings (Box 4, Folder 14.2)
      Woodland (Calif.) -- History; Rugby football; Slater, Colby E.; Olympic Games (8th: 1924: Paris, France)
    - Clipping, Berkeley rugby hero writes of Olympic victory, [1924]; D394.6.2.87; 2 clippings (Box 4, Folder 14.3)
    - Clipping, San Francisco Chronicle. French sporting experts disgusted. Not fair to blame nation, May 20, 1924; D394.6.2.88 (Box 4, Folder 14.4)
    - Clipping, Bobbed hair is style in France; Slater, [1924]; D394.6.2.89 (Box 4, Folder 14.5)
      France -- Social life and customs; Slater, Colby E.
    - Clipping, Slater, Farish go cabareting with Price of Wales. Not real spirit of France, wires Olympic chairman, May 20, 1924; D394.6.2.90 (Box 4, Folder 14.6)
    - Clipping, Paris sportsmen praise Americans, [1924]; D394.6.2.91 (Box 4, Folder 14.7)
    - Clipping, [Woodland Daily Democrat?]. Superiority against tempremental French, [1924]; D394.6.2.92 (Box 4, Folder 14.8)
    - Clipping, U.S. rugby team is banqueted, [1924]; D394.6.2.93 (Box 4, Folder 14.9)
    - Clipping, [Woodland Daily Democrat?]. Slater speaks at big victory banquet; sails for America Wednesday. French consul regrets riot of football crowd, May 20, 1924; D394.6.2.94 (Box 4, Folder 14.10)
    - Clipping, At Bay meeting, [1924]; D394.6.2.95; Clipping is torn. (Box 4, Folder 15.1)
    - Clipping, Woodland Daily Democrat. Football and basketball attracted considerable attention from "Daddy", 1926; D394.6.2.96 (Box 4, Folder 15.2)
    - Clipping, Berkeley man mentioned by French star, [1924]; D394.6.2.97 (Box 4, Folder 15.3)
      Rugby football; Rugby football teams -- New Zealand; Slater, Colby E.; Olympic Games (8th: 1924: Paris, France)
    - Clipping, Notes from Paris by Frederick W. Clampett, [1924]; D394.6.2.98; 3 clippings (Box 4, Folder 15.4)
    - Clipping, Through France with the American rugby team, by "Dud" de Groot, [1924]; D394.6.2.99; 3 clippings (Box 4, Folder 15.5)
    - Clipping, [Woodland Daily Democrat]. American flag flying over Fr[ance], May 1924; D394.6.2.100 (Box 7, Folder 5.1)
    - Clipping, [Various headlines], May 1924; D394.6.2.101 (Box 7, Folder 5.2)
      "American Flag Flying Over France's Gridiron", " U. S. Rugby Winners Booed in Paris", "Hiss U. S. Flag as Yankees Win Olympic Title", "U. S. Rugby Team Defeats France, 17 to 3", "Two Americans Mobbed at Olympic Games"
    - Clipping, But Yanks win by 17-3 score as French razz, by Henry Wales, May 18, 1924; D394.6.2.102; 2 clippings (Box 7, Folder 5.3)
    - Clipping, San Francisco Chronicle. French riot as U. S. team wins, May 19, 1924; D394.6.2.103 (Box 7, Folder 5.4)
    - Clipping, Les athlètes Américains battent facilement les rugbymen Roumains, [1924]; D394.6.2.104 (Box 7, Folder 5.5)
    - Clipping, Les débuts des Américains, [1924]; D394.6.2.105 (Box 7, Folder 5.6)
    - Clipping, Les débuts victorieux des Américains, [1924]; D394.6.2.106 (Box 7, Folder 5.7)
    - Clipping, Le match de rugby France-Amérique, 19 mai 1924; D394.6.2.107 (Box 7, Folder 5.8)
    - Clipping, Le match Amérique-Roumanie, [1924]; D394.6.2.108 (Box 7, Folder 5.9)
    - Clipping, Slater friends given half-day more to join in friendship fund, [1924]; D394.6.2.109 (Box 7, Folder 5.10)
    - Clipping, Woodland Daily Democrat. Slater elected captain of All-American rugby team; Legion pays honor, April 3, 1924; D394.6.2.110 (Box 7, Folder 5.11)
    - Clipping, Fans make register jingle for Babe Slater, [1924]; D394.6.2.111 (Box 7, Folder 5.12)
    - Clipping, [San Francisco Chronicle]. [Babe Slater] will head American ruggers against Rumania, May 10, 1924; D394.6.2.112 (Box 7, Folder 5.13)
    - Clipping, How many do you know?, [1924]; D394.6.2.113 (Box 7, Folder 5.14)
      "Photo of the Yankee rugby team and the Black Shirts of England"
    - Scrapook page with seven clippings attached, [1924]; D394.6.2.114 (Box 7, Folder 5.15)
      Woodland (Calif.) -- History; Rugby football; Olympic Games (8th: 1924: Paris, France); Slater, Colby E.; Picnic Day; University of California, Davis
    - Scrapbook page with four clippings attached, [1924]; D394.6.2.115 (Box 7, Folder 5.16)
    - Clipping, Sporting. Le match États-Unis-Roumanie, [1924]; D394.6.2.116; Four sheets attached at edge (Box 7, Folder 5.17)
    - Photocopies of oversized clippings, [1924]; D394.6.2.117; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 5.18)
      Photocopies of most clippings in 7:5
  - Ephemera, 1924; D394.6.3; 4 folders (Box 4, Folder 16-18)
    - Rugby Match Program, April 23, 1924; D394.6.3.1 (Box 7, Folder 6.1)
    - Rugby Match Program, April 26, 1924; D394.6.3.2 (Box 7, Folder 6.2)
    - Olympic Games Rugby Program, May 1924 (Box 7, Folder 6.3)
  - Photographs, 1924; D394.6.4; 28 folders. (Box 4, Folder 19-45, Box 7, Folder 7)
    - United States Olympic Rugby Team, 1924; D394.6.4.1; 1 photographic print black and white 9 x 14 cm (Box 4, Folder 19)
      Image is on photograph postcard. Norman Slater: top row, second from right.
    - United States Olympic Rugby Team at Dock, 1924; D394.6.4.2; 1 photographic print black and white 17 x 23 cm (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - France versus United States at Colombes: The Two Captains and the Referee, May 18, 1924; D394.6.4.3; 1 photographic print black and white 13 x 18 cm (Box 4, Folder 21)
      "Colombes 18-5-24. Les deux capitaines et l'arbitre. Cl. C.O.D. 783."
    - France versus United States at Colombes: United States Team Photograph, May 18, 1924; D394.6.4.4; 1 photographic print black and white 13 x 18 cm; Photograph pasted to two other photographs. (Box 4, Folder 22.1)
    - France versus United States at Colombes: Players Running on Field, May 18, 1924; D394.6.4.5; 1 photographic print black and white 13 x 18 cm; Photograph pasted to two other photographs. (Box 4, Folder 22.2)
    - France versus United States at Colombes: Players Jumping for Ball, May 18, 1924; D394.6.4.6; 1 photographic print black and white 13 x 18 cm; Photograph pasted to two other photographs. (Box 4, Folder 22.3)
    - France versus United States at Colombes: Players Lined up on Field, May 18, 1924; D394.6.4.7; 1 photographic print black and white 13 x 18 cm (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - France versus United States at Colombes: Players Lined up on Field, May 18, 1924; D394.6.4.8; 1 photographic print black and white 13 x 18 cm (Box 4, Folder 24)
      Photograph taken from stands.
    - France versus United States at Colombes: Players Running on Field, May 18, 1924; D394.6.4.9; 1 photographic print black and white 13 x 18 cm (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - France versus United States at Colombes: Players Jumping for Ball, May 18, 1924; D394.6.4.10; 1 photographic print black and white 13 x 18 cm (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - France versus United States at Colombes: Players Running on Field, May 18, 1924; D394.6.4.11; 1 photographic print black and white 13 x 18 cm (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - France versus United States at Colombes: Players Mid-Pass, May 18, 1924; D394.6.4.12; 1 photographic print black and white 13 x 18 cm (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - France versus United States at Colombes: Players Mid-Pass, May 18, 1924; D394.6.4.13; 1 photographic print black and white 13 x 18 cm (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - France versus United States at Colombes: Long-Distance View of Players Running on Field, May 18, 1924; D394.6.4.14; 1 photographic print black and white 13 x 18 cm (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - France versus United States at Colombes: Players During Pass, May 18, 1924; D394.6.4.15; 1 photographic print black and white 13 x 18 cm (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - France versus United States at Colombes: Players in Scrum, May 18, 1924; D394.6.4.16; 1 photographic print black and white 13 x 18 cm (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - France versus United States at Colombes: Players During Pass, May 18, 1924; D394.6.4.17; 1 photographic print black and white 13 x 18 cm; Photograph pasted to one other photograph. (Box 4, Folder 33.1)
    - France versus United States at Colombes: Players After Pass, May 18, 1924; D394.6.4.18; 1 photographic print black and white 13 x 18 cm; Photograph pasted to one other photograph. (Box 4, Folder 33.2)
    - France versus United States at Colombes: Player Running with Ball, May 18, 1924; D394.6.4.19; 1 photographic print black and white 13 x 18 cm; Photograph is torn. (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - France versus United States at Colombes: Players Rushing for Ball, May 18, 1924; D394.6.4.20; 1 photographic print black and white 13 x 18 cm; Photograph is torn. (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - France versus United States at Colombes: Players Jumping for Ball, May 18, 1924; D394.6.4.21; 1 photographic print black and white 13 x 18 cm (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - France versus United States at Colombes: Players in Scrum, May 18, 1924; D394.6.4.22; 1 photographic print black and white 13 x 18 cm (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - France versus United States at Colombes: Players Running on Field, May 18, 1924; D394.6.4.23; 1 photographic print black and white 13 x 18 cm (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - France versus United States at Colombes: Players Jumping for Ball, May 18, 1924; D394.6.4.24; 1 photographic print black and white 13 x 18 cm (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - France versus United States at Colombes: Player Running with Ball, May 18, 1924; D394.6.4.25; 1 photographic print black and white 13 x 18 cm (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - France versus United States at Colombes: Players on Field, May 18, 1924; D394.6.4.26; 1 photographic print black and white 13 x 18 cm (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - France versus United States at Colombes: Players After Tackle, May 18, 1924; D394.6.4.27; 1 photographic print black and white 13 x 18 cm (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - France versus United States at Colombes: Players Running as a Group, May 18, 1924; D394.6.4.28; 1 photographic print black and white 13 x 18 cm (Box 4, Folder 43)
    - France versus United States at Colombes: Players in Scrum, May 18, 1924; D394.6.4.29; 1 photographic print black and white 13 x 18 cm (Box 4, Folder 44)
    - France versus United States at Colombes: Players in Scrum, May 18, 1924; D394.6.4.30; 1 photographic print black and white 13 x 18 cm (Box 4, Folder 45)
    - U.S. Olympic Rugby Team in [London?], 1924; D394.6.4.31; 1 photographic print black and white 24 x 29 cm (Box 7, Folder 7)
      On verso: "Photo by H. Wayland, Rembrandt House Blackheath S. E. 3"
      Rugby football teams -- United States; Rugby football; Olympic Games (8th: 1924: Paris, France); Slater, Colby E.; Slater, Norman B. (Norman Bernard), 1894-1979
  - Scrapbook covers, 1924; D394.6.5 (Box-folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1924; D394.6.6; 4 items
    - Letter from Colby E. "Babe" Slater to his Mother, May 6, 1924; D394.6.6.1; Slater, Colby E.; 1 item (Box 4, Folder 46.1)
    - Letter from Norman Slater to sister Marguerite, May 12 1924; D394.6.6.2; Slater, Norman B. (Norman Bernard), 1894-1979; Messenger, Marguerite Slater; 1 postcard (Box 4, Folder 46.2)
      Rugby football teams -- United States; Messenger, Marguerite Slater; Olympic Games (8th: 1924: Paris, France)
    - Letter from Colby E. "Babe" Slater to his brother-in-law A.P. Messenger, May 26, 1924; D394.6.6.3; Slater, Colby E.; 1 item (Box 4, Folder 46.3)
    - Letter from Colby E. "Babe" Slater to his sister Marguerite, June 22, 1924; D394.6.6.4; Slater, Colby E.; Messenger, Marguerite Slater; 1 item (Box 4, Folder 46.4)
- Realia, 1912-2014; Series 7; 39 items.
  The majority of these items are medals and charms that Slater earned by winning athletic competitions including rugby at the Olympic Games.
  - Chain and charms, 1912-1928; D394.7.1; 1 chain, 8 charms. (Box-folder 8.1)
  - Medal, "VII Olympiad, Anvers", 1920; D394.7.2; 2-1/4 inch diameter. (Box-folder 8.2)
  - Medal, Pacific Association Championship, American Legion Basketball Team, 1922; D394.7.3 (Box-folder 8.3)
  - Elk's tooth charm, Woodland (Calif.) Lodge no.1299, [1924]; D394.7.4 (Box-folder 8.4)
  - Card/receipt case, [1924]; D394.7.5 (Box-folder 8.5)
  - Medal, "Olympic Games, Paris, Colby E. Slater, Captain", 1924; D394.7.6; 2-3/4 x 1-1/2 inches. (Box-folder 8.6)
  - Medal with ribbon, "Officiel, C. O. F., VIII Olympiade, Paris", 1924; D394.7.7 (Box-folder 8.7)
  - Medal, "Concurrent, C. O. F., VIII Olympiade, Paris", 1924; D394.7.8 (Box-folder 8.8)
  - Medal, "VIII Olympiade, Paris", 1924; D394.7.9; 2-1/8 inch diameter. (Box-folder 8.9)
  - Medal with ribbon, "On behalf of the City of New York to the victorious American athletes on their return from the Olympic Games", 1924; D394.7.10 (Box-folder 8.10)
  - Medal, "Aeros Sport", undated; D394.7.11 (Box-folder 8.11)
  - Charm, Cal Aggie Alumni Association, University of California, Davis, undated; D394.7.12 (Box-folder 8.12)
  - Name tag, Yolo County Farm Bureau, circa 1952; D394.7.13 (Box-folder 8.13)
  - Pennant with Olympic Rings, circa 1924; D394.7.14 (Box-folder 8.14)
  - Frame, undated; D394.7.15 (Box-folder 8.15)
  - Metal plates from German aircraft, circa 1918; D394.7.16; 2 items (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Ribbon, "California", undated; D394.7.17 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Packaging, 1962, undated; D394.7.18; 7 items (Box 5, Folder 3-5)
  - Watch, undated; D394.7.19 (Object 1)
  - Gift trophy to "C.E. Slater" for efficient leadership as 1917 General Chair of Picnic Day, D394.7.20 (Object 2)
  - U.S. Rugby Hall of Fame ring presented to C.E. Slater in 2013, Houston, TX, D394.7.21 (Object 3)
  - Framed Olympic Diploma, 1920; D394.7.22 (Frame 1)
  - Framed Olympic Diploma, 1924; D394.7.23 (Frame 2)
  - Rugby Team Jersey, 2014; D394.7.24 (Box 14)
    Jersey (USA Rugby by Canterbury) signed by 18 members of the U.S. Eagles Women's 7s Olympic team in residence at the Chula Vista Olympic Training Center, 7 February 2014
  - Berkeley High School Hall of Fame framed plaque for "Colby 'Babe' Slater", undated; D394.7.25 (Box 15)
  - Medal Case and Mailing Box, 1931?; D394.7.26 (Box 16, Item 1)
  - 1924 Olympics Ashtray, circa 1924; D394.7.27; Oval-shaped bronze (?) ashtray with raised figure of rugby player. (Box 16, Item 2)
  - California Alumni Association Card, 6 November 1950; D394.7.28 (Box 12, Folder 14)
    Slater, Colby E. -- Archives; California Alumnni Association -- History; University of California, Davis -- Alumni and alumnae
- Exhibit Materials, 2004-2005; Series 8; 1 linear foot (Box 11, Box 14)
  Labels, posters, and reproductions from exhibits.
- Addenda, 2017; Series 9
  - City of Berkeley Ordinance #464 N.S. Landmark Application: Captain John Slater House, 1335 Shattuck Avenue, Berkeley, CA 94709, January 26, 2017 (Box 12, Folder 12)
    Berkeley (Calif.) -- History; Slater family